A comedy from the heart that goes for the throat.
As Good as It Gets is a drama, comedy, romance film directed by James L. Brooks.
A misanthropic author, a single mother and waitress, and a gay artist form an
unlikely friendship after the artist is assaulted in a robbery.
Melvin Udall, played by Jack Nicholson.
Carol Connelly, played by Helen Hunt.
Simon Bishop, played by Greg Kinnear.
Frank Sachs, played by Cuba Gooding Jr..
Beverly Connelly, played by Shirley Knight.
Spencer Connelly, played by Jesse James.
As Good as It Gets is a 1997 American romantic comedy film directed by James L.
Brooks from a screenplay he co-wrote with Mark Andrus.
It stars Jack Nicholson as a misanthropic, bigoted  and obsessive–compulsive novelist, Helen Hunt
as a single mother with a chronically ill son, and Greg Kinnear as a gay artist.
The film was produced by TriStar Pictures and Gracie Films
and distributed by Sony Pictures Releasing.
As Good as It Gets premiered at the Regency Village Theatre on December 6, 1997,
and was released theatrically in the United States on Christmas Day.
A critical and box office hit, it grossed $314.1
million on a $50 million budget.
At the 70th Academy Awards, the film was nominated in
seven categories, including Best Picture.
Nicholson won for Best Actor and Hunt for Best Actress, making it
the most recent film to win both lead acting awards.
It is ranked 140th on Empire magazine's "The 500
Greatest Movies of All Time" list.
The film explores themes of new york city, friendship,
waitress, single parent, restaurant.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.